Charles Bukowski papers, 1958-1988
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of Charles Bukowski, 1958-1980
MS 171
Bukowski, Charles
The bulk of the collection consists of magazines and anthologies that contain Bukowski's contributions; also includes books translated into other languages. Correspondence varies from that of friends and fans, to business correspondence with presses and magazines.
9.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Charles Bukowski (1920-1994) was born in Andernach, Germany and came to the U.S. when he was three. He grew up in Los Angeles and began writing as a child. He published his first story at age 24 and first poem at age 35. He spent much of his life drifting. Although Bukowski did not associate with "beat writers," his style attracts readers and followers of the beat generation. A prolific writer, much of his work is based on his own experience using the language and subjects of the street. He wrote long-hand, much of it sent to publishers and never seen again. Bukowski became widely known after the movie "Barfly" which was based on his life around the time Factotum was written and featured Mickey Rourke. Bukowski wrote the screenplay and was involved with the movie production. Prior to "Barfly", he was best known by the public for his novel Post Office. In literary circles, Bukowski was praised for his poetry. Yet, he had a strong disregard for formal structure and did not consider himself a poet. He died in his adopted hometown of San Pedro, California.
Organization
This collection is organized into six series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1971-1978
Series II: Poetry and Prose Manuscripts, 1971-1978
Series III: Magazine Publications, 1958-1978
Series IV: Miscellaneous Publications, 1966-1980
Series V: Foreign Language Publications, 1973-1979
Series VI: Miscellaneous Oversize Materials, Notes of a Dirty Old Man, 1976-1976
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of magazines and anthologies that contain Bukowski's contributions; also includes books translated into other languages. Correspondence varies from that of friends and fans, to business correspondence with presses and magazines. Most of the manuscripts are typescript; some have edits, and some are signed and dated. These manuscripts of poems and prose often contain edge of society themes. Original appearances of Notes of a Dirty Old Man date from 1967- 1976. Ephemera consists of posters, announcements of readings, undated photographs of Bukowski, and two acrylic drawings signed by him.
Some items in German, French, Italian, Spanish and Dutch.
Related Material
Other materials by and about Bukowski are located in the Papers of Charles Bukoswki (MS 148) and Loujon Press Collection Relating to Charles Bukowski (MS 291).
Access Terms
Bukowski, Charles -- Archives
Poets, American -- 20th century -- Sources
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Sources
Underground press publications -- Specimens
Correspondence
Photographs
Poems
Manuscripts
Periodicals
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1971-1978
  - General Correspondence: A. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Arcade. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: B. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: Babbage, Joan. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Beighle, Linda Lee. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Bennett, John. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Best Cellar Press. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence: Black Sparrow Press. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence: C. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence: Canson, Katherine W. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence: City Lights. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence: Cravens, Nancy. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence: D. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence: Danz, Linda. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence: Douskey, Franz. 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence: E. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Éditions du Sagittaire. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: Eisele, Dick. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: F. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Fauser, Jörg. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Fett, Heinrich (uncle of C.B.). 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Flynn, Nancy. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence: G. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence: H. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence: Hackett, Philip. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence: Hornig, Jenny. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence: Hustler Magazine Inc. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence: I. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence: J. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence: Jordan, Pierrette. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence: Joris, Pierre. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence: K. 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence: King, Linda, Margie, Gerry, Ann (also see Menebroker, Ann). 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence: L. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Larson, Cynthia. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: Lawrence, Peter. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: Levine, Joan. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Ligi, Gary E. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Litmus, Inc. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Locklin, Gerry. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence: London Magazine. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence: Ma-Me. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence: Mi---. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence: Mallory, Lee. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence: Malone, Hank. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence: Maro Verlag. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence: Masarik, Al. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence: Menebroker, Ann. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence: New York Quarterly. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence: Nola Express. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence: Norse, Harold. 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence: O. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Ohio Review. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: P. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: Pearl. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Penfold, Gerda. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Pitts, James. W. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Planteen, Jojo and Pete (brother). 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence: Pleasants, Ben. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence: Pomegranate Press. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence: Q. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence: R. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence: Rabe, Claire. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence: Rael, Jimmy Gabe. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence: Richmond, Steve. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence: Riesenfeld, Stella. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence: Robertson, Kell. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence: Robson, Bill. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence: Rodriguez, Rosa. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence: Rolling Stone. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence: Roman, Jim. 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence: Sa-Se. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Sh---. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: St. Claire, Suzanne. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: Schenker, Don. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Scree. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Second Coming. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Sedriks, Andre and "Duck." 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence: Sheffield, Susanna Duncan. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence: Sherman, Jory. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence: Smith, Frances and Marina (daughter). 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence: Starczenko, Oksanna. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence: T. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence: U. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence: University of California, Santa Cruz. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence: University of Nebraska at Omaha. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence: Unmuzzled Ox. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence: V. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence: Vaubel, Libby. 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence: W. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence: Weissner, Carl. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: Williams, Miller. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence: Williamson, James R. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence: Winter, Nina. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence: Y-Z. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence: Zweitausendeins 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fan Letters: A. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fan Letters: B. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fan Letters: C. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fan Letters: D. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fan Letters: E. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fan Letters: F. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fan Letters: G. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Fan Letters: H. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fan Letters: J. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Fan Letters: K. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Fan Letters: L. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fan Letters: M. 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Fan Letters: N. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fan Letters: O. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fan Letters: P. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fan Letters: R. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fan Letters: S. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Fan Letters: T. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fan Letters: U. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fan Letters: V. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fan Letters: W. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Fan Letters: Y-Z. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Unidentifed: A-L. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified: M---. 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Series II: Poetry and Prose Manuscripts, 1971-1978
  - Poetry Manuscripts: "the sex fiends," and "an answer to an article upon my decadence and depravity." 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Includes:
    "40,000 flies"
    "the ladies of summer"
    "zoo"
    "back ups"
  - Poetry Manuscripts: Workbook Containing Poems, Notes, Drawings, and Cartoons. 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    "Balance Sheet, May 14, 1974"
    "free"
    "the big football game"
    "flashing white teeth"
    "UTAH"
    "feed time"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    "The Hollywood Hustle"
    "you"
    "the professors"
    "finger"
    "IN MEMORY OF THE SECOND LEADING JOCKEY AT SANTA ANITA"
    "46 and 9/10's"(extracted from notes)
    "sailing up your yellow river" (two versions)
    "but the stockmarket went up today"
    "funny man"
    "the girls in pantyhose at bus stop benches"
    "the famous man"
    "the machine"
    "the sex goddess"
    "rip tide"
    "BLUEBIRD"
    "an answer to a week's worth of mail"
    "the lady's man"
    "profit-taking"
    "I've seen the many glazed-eyed bums sitting under a bridge drinking cheap wine"
    "I was born in Andernach, Germany August 16, 1920"
    ""we all have hand guns and switchblades around here"
    "It's all a matter of the gate---"
    "now if you were teaching creative writing, he asked, what would you tell them"
    "the good life"
    "An Art"
    "the hungry madness of a miracle"
    "the Word"
    "ALL THOSE SOUNDS OF SEX AND LOVE AND LONLINESS WHILE WE POSE AS ARTISTS"
    "A NOTE UPON A WORKSHOP INSTRUCTOR WITH TINY HAIRS UNDER HIS CHIN"
    "DRUNK UPON THE CONTINENT OF THE DREAM"
    "all the spies to numb your ass and your brain and your heart"
    "Chopin Bukowski"
    "the thing"
    "5/1/75"
    "about crabs and things"
    "doom and siesta time"
    "the great film director"
    "my lucky friend"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    "the meek have inherited"
    "who in the hell is Tom Jones?"
    "the red pigeon"
    "those flashes..."
    "bright spots of light or serpents"
    "AT&T"
    ""an ounce of prevention is worth it"
    "I watch those thin-hoofed beasts"
    "sitting in a sandwich joint just off the freeway" (two versions).
    "some people ask for it"
    "and a horse with greenblue eyes walks on the sun"
    "the claws of Paradise"
    "one for the Jag"
    "the good loser"
    "to the soul-seekers"
    "guru"
    "airplane spin"
    "the fathead"
    "a lovely couple" (photocopy; on reverse side is an undated letter from Dave Herman with explanation).
    "I'd like a mermaid"
    "visitor"
    "about this thing we bother with"
    "JONES"
    " milk a cow and get milk"
    ""the meaning"
    "Ezra's dead; don't splash me with your horseshit"
    "the gloomy lady"
    "space is everywhere"
    ""trench warfare"
    "the insane always loved me"
    "the fisherman"
    "full moon"
    "in al fairness"
    "the girls at the green hotel" (earlier version)
    "one for Rochelle Owens"
    "on the big perfume contract"
    "clean old man"
    "piranhas"
    "yet it's still a long way to St. Louis" (two versions)
    "ask the butterfly"
    "the big score"
    "out on the branch"
    "the girls at the green hotel" (later version)
    "problems in American and Los Angeles"
    "all God's rats"
    "will the real thing please stand up and wave a wooden arm?"
    "an unusual place"
    "arena"
    "fast fuck"
    "garter belt"
    "the worst and the best"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    "the genius"
    "half a goldfish"
    "rain or shine"
    "my father and the bum"
    "luck from a dirty kitchen"
    "overcast"
    "the anarchists"
    "the joke"
    "thoughts from a stone bench in Venice"
    "Nava, and life"
    "chauv poems"
    "cockroach"
    "mean and stingy"
    "note upon the end of an affair"
    "no fuck"
    "the imagination and the reality"
    "all the little girls"
    "the price"
    "little tigers everywhere"
    "a definition"
    "further stanzas of 'a definition'"
    "junkies"
    "Texsun"
    "I never knew anybody"
    "near a plateglass window"
    "stolen"
    "2 horsecollars"
    "Nellie Fox, MVP"
    "the place didn't look that bad"
    "murder"
    "Chicago"
    "an acceptance slip"
    "figs"
    "the hallelujah chorus"
    "the silver mirror (for Georgia K.)" (two versions)
    "let's write" (extracted from notes)
    "warm water bubbles" (extracted from notes, two versions)
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    "on photographs"
    "how come you're not unlisted?"
    "January 1976"
    "white like snow"
    "traffic signals"
    "dead now"
    "communion"
    "a corny poem"
    "darling"
    "ah, shit"
    "twins"
    "the march"
    ""the girl on the bus stop bench"
    "life off of Hollywood and Western"
    "coupons"
    "fear"
    "prayer for a whore in bad weather"
    "a touch of steel"
    "she came out of the bathroon with her flaming red hair and said---"
    "the death kiss"
    "shit, sometimes it gets so lonely I can't even commit suicide"
    "coke blues"
    "this then"
    "trap"
    "her Porshe is a pale pink"
    "sex"
    "the promise"
    "the 6 foot goddess (for S.D.)"
    ...last page ( stanza) of a poem
    "beer"
    "Longshot"
    "beds, toilets, you and me"
    "liberty"
    "the fortune teller" (first of four versions of this poem)
    "the poem of the empty bed"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    "Me and Irwin Shaw"
    "waving and waving goodbye"
    "the fortune teller" (three versions of this poem)
    "BE ALONE"
    "defeat becomes habitual"
    "the beautiful young girl walking past the graveyard--"
    "How to be a great writer"
    "a stethoscope case"
    "DON'T TOUCH THE GIRLS"
    "QUIET CLEAN GIRLS IN GINGHAM DRESSES..."
    "against the tide"
    "the death trend"
    "light brown"
    "there was once a woman who put her head into an oven that I could have kissed with the most ultimate love possible"
    "the bee"
    "a floor job"
    "bedpans"
    "huge ear rings"
    "love"
    "weep"
    "war, and that particular bayonet"
    "for Al"
    "T.M."
    "through and through"
    "the retreat"
    "balls"
    "my friend Harry"
    "carrot"
    "another bed"
    "ashes"
    "bathtub"
    "she wrote me"
    "Carlton Way off Western"
    "225 pounds"
    "I'm as crazy as I ever was"
    "V.G."
    "goodbye, goodbye, clipped-winged bluebird"
    "103 degrees"
    "hunchback"
    "melancholia and the redhead"
    "a goodbye (for L.K.)"
    "madness"
    "bath #4"
    "Hang it up, Bukowski"
    "an unkind poem, they will say--"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    "note for my wall"
    "2 men at the track"
    "I need and I demand"
    "tangerines"
    "the woman from Germany"
    "rise, old purple snake"
    "Nana"
    "come back, you know who's best"
    ""rock"
    "here's for your nostalgia about the 50's and 60's"
    "operator"
    "the lady with the dog"
    "NOTE LEFT ON THE DRESSER BY A LADY FRIEND"
    "best bet"
    "William Burrows"
    "Horse and Fist"
    "Drain-o"
    "professional counseling"
    "men and urinals"
    "inflation and all"
    "Firing Squad"
    "lost dog"
    "post parade"
    "about a trip to Spain"
    "uggh..."
    "how ya gonna keep 'em down on the farm?"
    "the killer smiles"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    "59 cents a pound"
    "a matter of size"
    "8 rooms"
    "no place to hide"
    "mermaid"
    "a good show"
    "an observer"
    "a note upon waste"
    "these same walls"
    "respite"
    "The Beach Boys"
    "a note upon starvation"
    "the pretty girl who rented rooms"
    "I do it while thinking about things"
    "upon phoning an x-wife who I haven't seen for twenty years"
    "downtown"
    "she's free and wild"
    "the ladies who rip men apart"
    ""the old quarterback"
    "a most serious fellow"
    "Sam the mailman"
    "66 Volks mini-bus"
    "the firing of the canons"
    "notes upon an almost meaningless night"
    "a boy and his dog"
    "passport"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    "training instructions"
    "smashed"
    "an old jockey"
    "4 years hard time on Carlton Way"
    "yes"
    "some notes on the word and the way"
    "it's not strange"
    "we're all so wanted"
    "silk"
    "tongue-cut"
    "o, the literary life"
    "Purse $8,000. For three-year olds and upward. Three-year olds, 118 pounds; older, 120 lbs.. Non-winners at one mile or over since October 6 allowed 3 lbs; since July 25, 6 lbs. Claiming price $6,250. (Races when entered for $4,000 or less not considered.)"
    "the man on the bus stop bench"
    "Edith sent us"
    "exegesis"
    "11:45 p.m. discussion"
    "promenade"
    "the image"
    "and my mother had a nice umbrella and looked beautiful and funny in the rain..."
    "plate glass window"
    "the finish of Moby Dick"
    "the whores, the people at the taco stands, the bus drivers, the cops, the killers, the janitors, the highschool teachers, the priests, and the garbagemen"
    "there's one in every bar"
    "ow"
    "some thanks for some luck, temporary or otherwise" and untitlted poem
    "Venice, Calif., Nov. 1977"
    "snow goose"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    "my 2nd. and 3rd. jobs"
    "the interview"
    "the last night at the harness races"
    "with a crass lady in a big flower hat"
    "2 buddies"
    "2nd. street, near Hollister, in Santa Monica"
    "I drove her to the food stamp place and I had a hamburger while I waited and after a while we walked around and then"
    "the lady poet of unrelenting doom"
    "a large room and a small room"
    "a fact"
    "overt population"
    "he uses unwaxed dental floss"
    "double encounter of another kind"
    "high-roller"
    "panasonic"
    the deathly bravo"
    "letter"
    "the beast"
    "grandma"
    "platonic"
    "job #36"
    "legs"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    "a drink to that"
    "Hooked on H"
    "winter meeting"
    "time is made to be wasted"
    "suicide"
    "have a nice day"
    "Sibelius and etc."
    "the big weight-lifting feat"
    "Hollywood Ranch Market"
    "hot coffee"
    "a bad night for my buddy"
    "the indian"
    "Combat Primer"
    "it's not all wasted"
    "conversation"
    "coming"
    "info"
    "the way"
    "hot dog"
    "Christ in the Manger"
    "anonymity"
    "craft"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    "time off"
    "water bugs"
    "Hollywood" (an earlier version of "the dandy")
    "jilted"
    "my buddy"
    "the embracers"
    "the dandy"
    "the lodgers"
    "a member of the jury" (earlier version)
    "a member of the jury (later version)
    "so I got of the the AE-I"
    "Good Friday"
    "5000 dollars"
    "Europe"
    "those"
    "death of the toteboards, Hollywood Park, April 21, 1978"
    "legs, hips and behind"
    "the end of a short love affair"
    "the playboy of the Western world leaves the field to those who desire it--"
    "where's it at?"
    "the yards"
    "chilled"
    "Igloo"
    "crazy"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    "the weather's been fair"
    "racetrack"
    "travertine"
    "you can't make a lion out of a butterfly"
    "I.U.(C.)D:
    "Funny Man"
    "it's easy"
    "black"
    "all together now"
    "kuv stuff mox out"
    "the terrorists"
    "the girls are gone"
    "Rhine cruise"
    "Academy Award"
    "mosquito"
    "victory"
    "the whores of Hamburg"
    "4 Christs"
    "side show"
    "a great place"
    "mouth"
    "N.Y. Times"
    "there are hecklers in Germany too"
    "telephone"
    "the American writer"
    "bad fix"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    "head jobs"
    "tank jobs"
    "farewell"
    "the pros"
    "talk"
    "Pretty Boy"
    "fat head poem"
    "Sad letters from up North"
    "train station"
    "the trashing of the dildo"
    "gift"
    "a long hot day at the track"
    "EVEN CHATTERTON DRANK RAT POISON AND LEFT US AT PEACE"
    "a big Thursday night at Hollywood and Western"
    "the golden god"
    "Frankfurt guns"
    "EUROPE, AMERICA AND MY LIVER"
    "Mannheim, Germany, May 1978"
    "water the plants"
    "he used to be"
    "one-ball Willie"
  - Poetry Manuscripts. 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    "THE AVOIDANCE OF BOREDOM"
    "Brands"
    "the Chinaman did right"
    "ALL THE SACRED CHRISTS THAT NEVER ARRIVE"
    "ART CLASS"
    "belly"
    "Charles"
    "the creation of the morning line"
    "death"
    "The 4th of July Holiday"
    "the giraffes"
    "the glass fly"
    "a great man speaks of great men"